indiemoviesonline.com 2010-06-04

# Privacy policy | Free Movies Online | Watch Free Films | Indie Movies Online

**Privacy Policy**

**1\. Introduction and General Terms**

Indiemoviesonline.com, Inc. ("IMO") recognizes that its customers, visitors, Members, and others who use www.indiemoviesonline.com (the "IMO Site") (collectively or individually "Members") value their privacy. This Privacy Notice details important information regarding the use and disclosure of User information collected on the IMO Site. IMO provides this Privacy Notice to help you make an informed decision about whether to use or continue using the IMO Site. This Privacy Notice is incorporated into and is subject to the IMO Terms of Use. Your use of the IMO Site and any personal information you provide on the IMO Site remains subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice and our Terms of Use.

By visiting the IMO Site (whether or not you are a registered member) or using any of the IMO Services on any of the Sites, you are accepting this Privacy Policy. If you do not want information about you to be used in the manner set forth in this Privacy Policy, please do not use the IMO Services.

**2) The Information IMO Collects**

(i) Account Information: 

When you register, we may ask for information such as your name, email address, birth date & gender. From time to time, we  may also ask you optionally to provide other information. If you choose to provide such information, you are giving IMO the permission to use and store it consistent with this policy. Therefore, please understand when you sign in to the IMO site, you are not anonymous to us.

Account Information is used:

-   to personalize communications to you and identify you in our system.

-   for identity verification

-   emailing of system messages, personal IMO messages, IMO newsletters, special offers and other IMO communications.

-    to determine whether you are of legal age to view mature content.

(ii) Profile

Your supplied gender, age and chosen username will be displayed as part of your public profile, you may however, also elect to provide more information about yourself in your profile. IMO does not require you to fill out the extra fields on your profile in order to participate in the service or community.  IMO makes no claims about the privacy of publicly available profile information.

(iii) Cookies, log files and clear GIF information

When you visit the IMO Site, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. IMO uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser help file directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the IMO Site may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

When you use the IMO Site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser language, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

When you use the IMO Site, we may employ "clear GIFs" (a.k.a. Web Beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our Members anonymously (i.e., in a non-personally-identifiable manner). In addition, we may also use clear GIFs in HTML-based emails sent to our Members to track which emails are opened by recipients.

The cookies, log files and clear GIF information is used to:

-   remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the IMO Site;

-   provide custom, personalized content and information;

-   monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns;

-   monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.; 

-    track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions and contests;

-   determine where you are accessing the IMO site from geographically and which services are therefore available.

(iv) Surveys and polls:

IMO values opinions and comments from members, so we may conduct online surveys. Participation in these surveys is entirely optional. Typically, the information is aggregated and used to make improvements to IMO and to develop appealing content, features and promotions for members. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey.

(v) Forums, comments and private messaging

Any personally identifiable information you submit through the forums and comments system can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums or by private message to other users.

(vi) Combined information

We use both your personally identifiable information and certain non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous User usage data, cookies, IP addresses, browser type, clickstream data, etc.) to improve the quality and design of the IMO Site and to create new features, promotions, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing User preferences and trends

(vii) Anonymous aggregated data

Anonymous data is information (originally personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable) that subsequently is used in aggregate form. We may use anonymous data for purposes of research or analysis. We may conduct research on our customer demographics, internet usage, and interests and behavior based on personal data we gather. Although anonymous data may be based in part on personal data, it does not identify you personally. 

(viii) Film viewing history

IMO stores information about which films you watch in streaming flash format. The list of films is also posted to your public profile.

This information is used to:

-   improve the site experience.

-   allow friends to recommend movies to each other.

-   track film watches so we can return royalties to the film distributors. 

**3) When IMO Discloses Information**

(i) Site functionality and marketing

We do share non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous User usage data, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the IMO Site.

We may use your personally identifiable information to provide you with information about IMO's features, services, and other offerings that may be of interest to you;  send information or offers to users on behalf of IMO's partners (please note that if we were to do this, we would not give those partners personally identifiable information such as your name or address); or share your personally identifiable information with advertisers, business partners, and other entities that are not affiliated with IMO who would like to send you information about their products and services.

(ii) Contests

If you win a contest, we may post limited personally identifiable information on the IMO Site. However, we will notify you of this possibility when collecting personally identifiable information or we will obtain your consent.

(iii) IMO suppliers

We may share your personally identifiable information with companies that provide services to us, including outside contractors or agents who help us manage our information activities (for example, contest and sweepstakes administration). But they may only use your personally identifiable information to provide us with a specific service and not for any other purpose. Similarly, we may share your personally identifiable information with other people or entities in order to provide goods or services that you have requested or to complete a transaction at your request.

(iv) Legal requirements and IMO protection

There may be instances when we may disclose personally identifiable information without providing you with a choice in order to protect the legal rights of IMO or its affiliates, and each of their respective investors, directors, officers, employees, agents, and suppliers; to protect the safety and security of users of the IMO Services or to enforce our Terms of Use; to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or to comply with or respond to the law or legal process, whether or not legally required. If you submit a Notice of Copyright Infringement pursuant to the Terms of Use, we will send a copy to the person or entity who uploaded, stored, or transmitted the material addressed by the communication.

**4) Your Choices**

(i) Decline

You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through the IMO Site, in which case IMO may not be able to provide certain services to you. 

(ii) Responsibility

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you profile access or making corrections. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times. 

(iii) Contact Us

If you have concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, including if you believe that IMO may have incorrect information for you or if you would like your personally identifiable information to be permanently removed from our database, you may email us at privacy@Indiemoviesonline.com.

Emails sent to privacy@Indiemoviesonline.com for purposes other than communication about personally identifiable information may not be answered.

**5) Third-party Companies**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site we will ask you for your friend's name and email address.  We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. IMO stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. 

Your friend may contact us at [privacy@indiemoviesonline.com](mailto:privacy@indiemoviesonlin.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

The IMO Services may be linked to websites operated by other companies. Some of these websites may be co-branded with our name or logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by us. IMO is not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites operated by third parties that are linked to any of the Sites. Once you have left the IMO Site by clicking on a link, you should check the privacy policy of the other website to determine how it handles any personally identifiable information they collect from you.

IMO carries advertisements from other companies, often with the ability to click through to websites run by such other companies. IMO is not responsible for the privacy practices of advertisers. Once you have left the IMO Site by clicking on an advertisement, you should check the privacy policy of the advertiser to determine how it handles any personally identifiable information they collect from you. Please be aware that IMO does not warn you when you have chosen to link through to another website from the IMO Site.

Some of the advertisements that appear in connection with the IMO Services may be delivered to you by internet advertising companies (also called "ad networks" or "network advertisers"). These companies may use cookies and other technologies to deliver advertisements to you, measure their effectiveness, and personalize advertising content. IMO does not have access to or control over cookies or other technologies that they may use. The information practices of these advertising companies are governed by their own privacy policies and are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

Please note that if you are accessing IMO from outside the UK and you make a comment or complaint regarding any element of advertising (see paragraph 11 for more details about this) then IMO may forward your correspondence to IMO only for the purposes of responding to you.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>[ ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

**6) Data Security**  

(i) Safeguards

IMO uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to IMO and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, IMO makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

(ii) Notification 

If IMO learns of a security systems breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. IMO may post a notice on the IMO Site if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach you should notify us at privacy@indiemoviesonline.com.

(iii) Children

IMO does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information or non-personally-identifiable information on the IMO Site from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of our website is directed to persons under 13. If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not use or access the IMO Site at any time or in any manner unless under the supervision of a parent or guardian . If IMO learns that personally identifiable information of persons less than 13 years of age has been collected on the IMO Site without verified parental consent, then IMO will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. 

**7) International Members**

If you are a user accessing the IMO Site from a region outside Barbados, with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from Barbados laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the IMO Site, which are governed by Barbados law, this Privacy Notice, and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your personal information to Barbados and you consent to that transfer.

**8) Business Transitions**

In the event IMO goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred.  You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. 

**9) How long will IMO keep my personal information?**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant service, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with IMO. 

Where you contribute to www.indiemoviesonline.com IMO will generally only keep your content for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted.

**10) Changes to IMO's Privacy Policy**

From time to time, IMO may revise this Privacy Policy to reflect industry initiatives or changes in the law or to the scope of the IMO Services, among other reasons. Any revisions will be effective upon posting the new Privacy Policy on the IMO Site at [http://www.Indiemoviesonline.com/node/235](http://www.indiemoviesonline.com/node/235). Therefore, it is important to check  the Privacy Policy posted at this location each time you visit the IMO Site or use any of the IMO Services to ensure you are familiar with the most updated policies and practices. If you do not agree with any changes to the Privacy Policy, you must leave the IMO Site and discontinue any use of the IMO Services. Any visit to the IMO Site or use of the IMO Services on any of the Sites by you after the new Privacy Policy is posted will indicate your agreement to the new Policy.
